Let's start off by talking about work
and studies. Do you work or do you
study?
>> Currently, I just graduated so I'm in
between things but yeah I'm finding work
at this point.
>> Where would you like to find some work?
>> Ideally in Mumbai. I'm really interested
in like the startup industry. There are
some startups that I'm looking to work
with as in the moment right now. So
that's just what like this next chapter
holds for me. In 10 years time, what
career would you like to have?
>> Good question. Um, I really feel
strongly about philanthropy and
education specifically. So, I imagine
myself living in between like different
places in India. Um, pursuing this like
philanthropic educational
work. Yeah.
>> What did you want to be when you were a
little girl? ah so many things you know
it's kind of like I don't know I
couldn't choose I think every day was
something different um I would watch
like a really fun TV show and for
example suits and be like oh I'm going
to be a lawyer and I was convinced and
then I would watch a really fun movie
like Devil Wears Prada and I wanted to
be a fashion designer so it was many
different things when I was younger
>> now let's talk about reading did you
have a favorite book when you were a
child
>> so I don't I know if it's necessarily my
favorite, but there was this book called
The Secret Garden that I remember
reading in my class in the fourth grade,
and I'm categorizing it as my favorite
book because it just meant a lot to me
because there was really nice
descriptions about like the scenery, and
that really got me into reading. So, I
think for the heartwarming purpose, it's
definitely my favorite book when I was
younger, but it's just the book that
started my love for reading in general.
>> Did you do a lot of reading when you
were at university?
>> I did a lot of reading. Too much
reading. I did a lot of reading that was
more literary works and it made me
realize, oh, I I don't like it. I don't
like them. Um, I'm also not a fan of
novels, but what I am a fan of is more
fiction or self-help kind of books,
especially that I'm getting older and I
want to incorporate habits into my life.
>> Are there any books you would recommend
to people?
>> There's this book I read called Daisy
Jones and the Sixth, and it was just a
really fun book. It was the book I read
recently, and I think people who are
into fiction and like music would really
love that book. It was adapted into a
series after. So definitely recommend
that one.
>> Now let's talk about drinks. In your
country, what do people normally drink
with dinner?
>> Okay. There's so many options. Um,
particularly in my family, we have a
weird mix of things, but in my country,
we usually have like masala chai or we
have normal sodas, but we put some
masala in it, which is like some spice
to kind of give it that extra like kick.
So that's really common. But in my
family, we put like for example Coke, we
put a little bit of vanilla ice cream.
And I think it also has to do with like
different places in India also have
this. But in my family, it's stable.
Yeah.
>> Do you drink a lot of water every day?
>> Yes, I do. And it's because when I
don't, I can feel the like adverse
effects immediately. So I make sure I
drink water every single day. But it's
so hard because like in the hurry of
everything, you just forget.
>> Do you prefer drinking tea or coffee?
>> Okay, so I have I have phases in my
life. Like sometimes coffee just tastes
too good, but I'm really caffeine
sensitive. I've realized this after
having very like jittery episodes. So if
I have coffee, it's a decaf, but I
really love tea for like different
purposes. So like chamomile before
sleeping or green tea to detox.
>> If I visited your home, what would you
or your parents or your family offer me
to drink?
>> Definitely tea. I think it's also like
culturally like we're more accustomed to
being like can I get you some tea? So
definitely tea, but also like coffee is
always available if you want. But s
request.
>> Now let's talk about the weekend. What
do you normally do on the weekend?
>> So I think it depends on how the the
week has gone. If it's a good week, you
know, weekend can go any which way. But
I think a very crucial point or part of
my routine is like cold plunging or
sauna. I really try and prioritize that
because it helps like my anxiety fade
away. Um, I really love exercising.
That's a crucial part as well. Um, and
just meeting friends and family. I think
I I carve out time specifically for that
because the weekdays can get so busy.
>> How often do you have a lazy weekend?
>> Very often. Like most mornings are like
they begin very lazily. And when it
comes to lazy weekends, I don't really
thrive on lazy weekends cuz then I kind
of fall into like a rut. So I try to be
lazy enough but not too lazy.
>> Do you think that your weekend schedule
will change as you grow older?
>> I definitely think so. I think that the
more I'm using a lot of energy during
the week and maybe doing tasks that
don't give me energy that are more
draining, I will need time to recuperate
like during the weekends. So, the more
I'm a little bit forced to do things I'm
not particularly happy about, I think
the more lazy weekends I need. The last
time I had to do something in a hurry
was quite recently. I think around a
month ago, I moved in. I moved out of
where I was living and it was in a
different country. So, what that meant
is I had to pack my whole life into two
suitcases since I was moving back home.
And the reason it was all left to the
last minute was because I had just went
on a trip with my boyfriend to Mexico.
So, I had around a week once I came back
from that trip to pack up everything, to
arrange where all my mattresses would
go, where my couch would go, and get rid
of everything. And it was quite an
anxietyinducing experience for me
because I'm a very like organized
person, even though this doesn't seem
like it, but I really am. And so when I
had to
kind of gather everything, it felt very
last minute. Even though I had a week
and I think till the last hour I had to
leave be like to go to the airport. I
was packing things up. But thankfully I
had really group like a really good
group of friends that were with me
blasting music, helping me pack made it
like a really fun enjoyable experience
and I think that really helped also get
some momentum to pack. Otherwise I was
feeling really lazy about it and I think
even after I left I left some things
behind but my friends went back to my
apartment helped me get rid of it. So it
was definitely a team effort. It takes a
village.
>> We've been discussing an occasion when
you had to do something in a hurry. And
we're going to talk about time
management, arriving late, managing
time, things like that. Do you think
it's acceptable to arrive late when
meeting a friend?
>> Thought about this question a lot
because I feel like I've been victim to
this situation a lot of the times. I
think it depends on how much it happens
with the same person. Um, but I think
there's obviously some unforeseen
circumstances that can arise. I would
say that if you can't avoid it cuz time
is really limited and you want to kind
of extend respect to your friend, show
them, you know, I care about your time.
So, it's always best to, I personally
think, try and arrive on time.
>> Should there be any negative
consequences for people who arrive late
for work? Again, it kind of what I said
before bleeds into this answer a little
bit because I think it's depending on
how recurring is your situation. Um, if
there's a certain circumstance that
happens every morning, maybe you know
you're a parent that has to take care of
your child, then I think the company
should allow for this situation to
happen and not give such extreme
consequences. I think they should be
more accepting and understanding. Um but
I think if it's just because you know
you've been waking up late for companies
even though I would personally I would
be like it's okay. I think you know time
is money especially nowadays in like
this corporate capitalistic world. So
unfortunately it makes sense for
companies to reprimand but I would say
not too much.
>> Now let's talk about managing study
time. Do you think it's better to study
for long periods of time or break up
study time into shorter chunks?
>> I would say shorter chunks. I'm also
saying this understanding the era we are
in now where short from media has also
influenced like how we consume
information and what works best for us.
So I think more than
what should people do, it's what I feel
would be most productive for them. And I
think that maybe like having little
breaks in between can be like kind of
motivation. Okay, let me finish this
chapter and then I'll have like a
chocolate. So I think that would be
really good.
>> Do you think that students should
incorporate leisure time into their
study time?
>> I think so. I recently went to this like
virtual VR ex like this experience where
I was learning about the Titanic by like
a VR headset and this so I found it like
a really fun experience. It was date
night for me, but I learned so much. And
my first thought after that experience
was I can have fun and learn and I felt
like my mom like being like you can have
fun and learn. But I think that they
both can go hand in hand, especially
nowadays cuz there's so many different
things available for you to really
expand how you like consume information.
So yeah, I think so.
>> Well done. That's the end of part three
and the end of the speaking test. How
did you feel about that?
>> So nice. I love it.
>> Yeah,
>> I think it was no problem for you.
>> Thank you.
>> As you probably heard, that was a very
high level response. What I've done is I
put her whole transcript into a PDF for
you and I've highlighted all the great
expressions, idiomatic language, grammar
structures, vocabulary for you so you
can learn from those very highle
answers. If you want that, all you have
to do is just go to the description or
the first pinned comment and you can
download that for free today. If you
want to watch another IEL speaking
video, click here. If you want help with
your IEL speaking test and you want some
tips, click